mdpi.com 2019-12-29

# MDPI | Privacy Policy

You can use * to search for partial matches. 

## Need Help?

### Support

Find support for a specific problem on the support section of our website. 

 Get Support 

### Feedback

Please let us know what you think of our products and services. 

 Give Feedback 

### Information

Our dedicated information section provides allows you to learn more about MDPI. 

 Get Information 

_clear_

We respect your concerns regarding privacy on the Internet and value the relationship we have with you. This policy outlines our efforts to protect your privacy, what kind of your data we collect and what we will do with the collected data. MDPI is an open access publisher and provides platforms for open scientific exchange. This Privacy Policy affects all websites and services that MDPI provides, including, but not limited to, [Sciforum](https://sciforum.net/), [Preprints](https://www.preprints.org/), [Scilit](https://www.scilit.net/), [Encylcopedia](https://encyclopedia.pub/), [WSForum](http://wsforum.org/) and [MDPI’s Submission System, “SuSy”](https://susy.mdpi.com/). 

§ 1

**Protection of Your Information**  

All data we collect from you on our websites is protected against unauthorized access by third parties. We do our utmost to protect your privacy through the appropriate use of security technologies and physical safeguards. 

§ 2

**Website Usage Information**  

While you use our websites, your visits to individual pages will be tracked and recorded in web server log files (“Log Data”). Log Data may be used by MDPI for statistical purposes, to recognize patterns of usage of the websites, and to improve the structure and content presentation. The usage information we collect (using [HTTP Cookies](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie)) includes referring URLs, browser and device characteristics, IP address, operating system, as well as dates and times of website visits. 

Via the website, MDPI may offer via its website third party services, such as article recommendations, social login, social sharing, and banners to third party sites. Information which is collected by MDPI when you access third party services is processed under this Privacy Policy, while information collected by third party operators themselves will be governed by their own privacy policies. 

When visiting our website, your browser may produce pop-up advertisements. These advertisements are produced by other websites you have previously visited or by third party software installed on your computer. MDPI does not authorize, endorse, or recommend products or services contained in such pop-ups advertisements. 

Our websites may use Google Analytics to help us collect information about how visitors use our sites. We use this information to compile reports and to help us improve the sites. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to a site, where visitors have navigated to a site from and the pages they visit whilst on a site. 

To view Google’s Privacy Policy, see [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en). 

You can configure your browser to opt out of providing data to Google Analytics by using the browser add-on provided by Google [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). 

§ 3

**User Accounts, Registration and Personalized Services**  

To make use of personalised services, you will have to register a user account with our websites. During registration we will ask you to provide some personal information, including, but not limited to, your name, valid e-mail address, affiliation, postal address, phone number, password, academic degree, position within your institution or organization, and your research interests. Some of this information is required to properly set up the user account for you to use all of MDPI’s services. MDPI may use this information to fulfil our contract with you (e.g. the publication of your article). Furthermore, MDPI may also use this information internally, e.g., to evaluate and improve our business, respond to any questions, requests or comments you make, for targeted marketing purposes, or to identify and prevent fraud, claims or other liabilities. MDPI may contact you by e-mail to draw your attention to content that might be of interest to you (e.g. new services, products or publications) and for other advertising. If the personal information was provided to us by a third party, MDPI may still use this information in the same manner as described above. You will have the chance to opt out of receiving such e-mails by unsubscribing or contacting the MDPI customer service at [__](mailto:support).

§ 4

**International Transfer of Personal Data**  

As an international company, MDPI may transfer your personal information outside of your country of residence to be stored on our servers. MDPI takes steps to ensure your personal information is continued to be protected wherever it is stored and/or processed. 

§ 5

**Your Rights**  

As a registered user, you can access your account at any time and make corrections or updates. In accordance with existing data privacy law, you may request the information that MDPI holds or processes about you. On request, we will also provide you with a copy of all personal information that we possess about you. We will delete this personal information when you request to deactivate your account. However, some personal information may remain in storage for a certain period of time in order to comply with our (legal) obligations and to resolve disputes. 

§ 6

**Linked Websites**  

MDPI may link to other websites not controlled by MDPI. Please take note that MDPI cannot be held responsible or liable for privacy practices of other websites, nor their services or content. 

§ 6

**Changes to the Privacy Policy**  

MDPI reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time by posting changes without prior notice. Please check this Privacy Policy periodically for any modifications. Your continued use of any service following the posting of any changes will mean that you have accepted and agreed to the changes. 

§ 7

**How To Contact Us**  

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, please contact us at [__](mailto:support).

This Privacy Policy was last updated on 17 May 2018
